YINLIN DENG

yinlind2@illinois.edu | dengyinlin.github.io

RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interest lies broadly in the intersection of software engineering and machine learning. I am interested in developing intelligent analysis, testing, verification, and synthesis techniques to improve the reliability, robustness, and performance of software systems, especially for machine learning systems.

Currently, I focus on testing machine learning libraries, which serve as the foundation for building, training, and deploying deep learning models. My previous work has helped to find **275** real-world bugs in popular open-source deep learning libraries including PyTorch, TensorFlow, JAX, and OneFlow.

EDUCATION

University of Illinois Urbana Champaign (UIUC)

Illinois, USA

Ph.D. student in Computer Science

2021—present

Advisor: Prof. Lingming Zhang Peking University

Beijing, China

B.Sc. in Computer Science, Turing Class

2017 - 2021

PUBLICATIONS

Fuzzing Deep-Learning Libraries via Automated Relational API Inference Yinlin Deng*, Chenyuan Yang*, Anjiang Wei, Lingming Zhang [paper] [code]

ESEC/FSE'22

Free Lunch for Testing: Fuzzing Deep-Learning Libraries from Open Source

ICSE'22

Anjiang Wei, Yinlin Deng, Chenyuan Yang, and Lingming Zhang [paper][code]

OOPSLA'22

Coverage-Guided Tensor Compiler Fuzzing with Joint IR-Pass Mutation

Jiawei Liu, Yuxiang Wei, Sen Yang, **Yinlin Deng**, and Lingming Zhang [paper][code][artifact]

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Intern at Fujitsu Research of America

June 2022-Aug. 2022

Topic: Feature engineering for Automated Machine Learning (AutoML)

Manager: Mukul Prasad, Mentor: Mehdi Bahrami

Research Intern at Microsoft Research, Asia

June 2020—Jan. 2021

Topic: Table range detection for Spreadsheet Intelligence

Manager: Shi Han, Mentor: Xiao Lv

STEP Intern at Google

July 2019-Sept. 2019

Topic: Static deep learning model compression for Federated Learning

HONORS & AWARDS

- SIGSOFT CAPS Travel Grant for ESEC/FSE 2022
- Gold Medal in the ICPC Asia-East Continent Final contest 2019
- Gold Medal in the ICPC Asia Regional Contest Nanjing Site 2019
- Most innovative Project in Google AI/ML Winter Camp Beijing Site 2019
- Merit student in Peking University 2017
- Silver Medal in the National Olympiad in Informatics (NOI) 2015

SERVICE

Co-Reviewer FSE'22, ASE'22.

^{*} denotes joint first authors.